List<Map<String, dynamic>> ECGPartThreeQuestions = [
  {
    'question':
        'Which lead on a 12-lead ECG is positioned at the fourth intercostal space at the anterior axillary line?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead V5.',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the significance of the PR interval on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'It represents atrial depolarization.',
      'It represents ventricular depolarization.',
      'It represents the isoelectric line between atrial and ventricular activity.',
      'It represents ventricular repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'A patient presents with a heart rate of 40 bpm, a regular rhythm, and wide QRS complexes. What is the likely diagnosis?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Ventricular tachycardia.',
      'Sinus bradycardia.',
      'Supraventricular tachycardia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which segment of the ECG is often used to evaluate for myocardial ischemia or infarction?',
    'answers': ['P segment.', 'PR segment.', 'QRS segment.', 'ST segment.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which electrolyte imbalance is associated with a prolonged QT interval and an increased risk of torsades de pointes?',
    'answers': [
      'Hypernatremia.',
      'Hypokalemia.',
      'Hypercalcemia.',
      'Hypocalcemia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the primary purpose of the P wave on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial depolarization.',
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
      'Atrial repolarization.',
      'Ventricular repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which arrhythmia is characterized by a rapid, irregular rhythm with narrow QRS complexes and no discernible P waves?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Atrial flutter.',
      'Ventricular tachycardia.',
      'Supraventricular tachycardia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the most common cause of an elevated ST segment in lead aVR on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Myocardial infarction.',
      'Pericarditis.',
      'Bundle branch block.',
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which electrolyte imbalance is associated with a prolonged PR interval and peaked T waves on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Hypernatremia.',
      'Hypokalemia.',
      'Hypercalcemia.',
      'Hypocalcemia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'A patient presents with ST-segment elevation in leads I, aVL, V5, and V6. Which coronary artery is likely occluded?',
    'answers': [
      'Left anterior descending (LAD).',
      'Left circumflex.',
      'Right coronary artery (RCA).',
      'Left main coronary artery.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which ECG lead is often used to diagnose left ventricular hypertrophy?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead V5.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question': 'In which lead is the R wave typically tallest?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead V4.',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the primary purpose of the QRS complex on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial depolarization.',
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
      'Atrial repolarization.',
      'Ventricular repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which arrhythmia is characterized by a regular rhythm and a wide QRS complex, often seen in patients with bundle branch block?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Atrial flutter.',
      'Ventricular tachycardia.',
      'Supraventricular tachycardia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the significance of the T wave on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial depolarization.',
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
      'Atrial repolarization.',
      'Ventricular repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which lead on a 12-lead ECG is positioned at the fourth intercostal space at the midclavicular line on the left side?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead V4.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the significance of the T wave on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial depolarization.',
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
      'Atrial repolarization.',
      'Ventricular repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which arrhythmia is characterized by a rapid, regular rhythm with narrow QRS complexes and inverted P waves?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Atrial flutter.',
      'Ventricular tachycardia.',
      'Supraventricular tachycardia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the most common cause of an elevated ST segment in lead aVR on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Myocardial infarction.',
      'Pericarditis.',
      'Bundle branch block.',
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which electrolyte imbalance is associated with a shortened QT interval on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Hypernatremia.',
      'Hypokalemia.',
      'Hypercalcemia.',
      'Hypocalcemia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which lead on a 12-lead ECG is positioned at the fourth intercostal space at the midaxillary line on the left side?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead V5.',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the significance of the PR interval on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'It represents atrial depolarization.',
      'It represents ventricular depolarization.',
      'It represents the isoelectric line between atrial and ventricular activity.',
      'It represents ventricular repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
];
